Emmy Lou Packard
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Reference Files on Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo, 1929-1986, Series 6:; (Box 5, 10, OV 11; 0.9 linear feet)
  - Sketches and Doodles by Frida Kahlo, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Sketches and Doodles by Diego Rivera (See Also OV 11), 1941, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Oversized Sketches and Doodles by Diego Rivera, 1941, undated (Box OV 11, Reel 5817)
  - Transcript of an Interview of Giacomo Patri by Packard, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Notebook concerning Repair of Rivera Fresco at San Francisco City College by Packard (includes photographs of Packard and Rivera), 1940-1982, (4 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Notes, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Notes from a Lecture by Rivera, 1930 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Writings, "An Account of Rivera's Work on the Fresco at the Golden Gate International Exposition, 1940", 1958 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Text for Packard's Unpublished Book, 1976-1985, (4 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "The Paintings of Emmy Lou Packard" by Diego Rivera, 1941 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Statement for the San Francisco Housing and Planning Association by Diego Rivera, 1941 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Discurso en el Aniversario de la Muerte de Frida Kahlo" by Juan O'Gorman, 1964 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Biographical Account of Packard by Sharon Patton, 1977 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Photograph of Ralph Stackpole with Rivera and Kahlo, 1931 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Photographs of Rivera, Rivera with Kahlo, Rivera with Packard, and Kahlo with Packard, 1941, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Photographs of Kahlo's Studio and Rivera's Pan American Unity Mural in San Francisco, 1941, 1959 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Packard at Kahlo's House/Museum, taken by Charles Irvine, 1976 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Photograph of Pablo O'Higgins, 1977 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Photograph of Aztec dancers celebrating Rivera's birthday in front of City College Fresco, 1981 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Photograph of Packard and Ruth Cravath by Don Beatty, 1982 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Photograph of Packard Authenticating a Rivera Fresco in Bellas Artes, Mexico City, 1982 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Photographs of Artwork by Kahlo, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Photographs of Artwork by Rivera, circa 1971 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Photographs of Artwork by Juan O'Gorman, 1977 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Oversized Photographs of Packard, Rivera, and Kahlo, 1941, undated (Box 10 (sol), Reel 5817)
  - Clippings, 1936-1983, undated, (3 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Exhibitions Announcements and Catalogs, 1978-1984 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1978, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
- Writings By Packard, 1953-1984, Series 7:; (Box 5; 17 folders)
  Writings (typescripts) by Packard concerning various political and art interests, arranged chronologically.
  - Biographical account, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Logging in Mendocino," undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Printmaking with Linoleum and Wood," undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Russian Art Today," undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Tide-pool Aquarium," undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Tribute to Charlie Safford," 1953 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Person to Person Call!," circa 1965 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Brussels," 1965 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Prague: From Baroque to the Non-Object," 1965 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Mendocino Artists Have Record Year," 1965 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "The Truth About Revolutionary Painters, The People, The USA, and All That Jazz If You Really Want to Know," 1965 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Impressions on Reading the Introduction, Chapter I and Chapter II of 'Fat Cats and Democrats' by Bill Domhoff," 1972 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Statement at the Time of Donald Cairns' Possible Dishonorable Discharge from the Army," 1972 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "To Those Who Ask Why I Don't Number or Limit Editions of My Hand Prints," 1975 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "American Graphic Art Exhibit in Uzbekistan", 1977 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "McCarthyism: Attack on the Arts and the Mass Media," for Meiklejohn Symposium, Berkeley, California, 1980 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Recollections of Byron Randall," 1983-1984 (Box 5, Reel 5817)
- Writings By Others, 1955-1984, undated, Series 8:; (Box 5-6; 19 folders)
  Writings (typescripts and manuscripts) by Other Authors concerning politics, art, and Packard's family.
  - "Richard Correll," by an unidentified author, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Ugli Amici di Reality," by Renato Guttuso, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Betrayal or Blessing, An Attempt to Analyze the Czechoslovak Occupation," by Hugh B. Hester, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Should Berkeley Own Its Own Power Distribution System and Buy Its Power from Some Suitable Public Agency," by Walter E. Packard, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "The Preservation of Public Art: Problems and Proposals," by Marlene Park, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Three Fables," by Allan Temko, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Four Fables," by Allan Temko, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - "Artists As Light Sharers," by Althya Clark Youngman, undated (Box 5, Reel 5817)
  - KCBS: "This is San Francisco: The Painted Birds," by J. G., 1955 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - "Indonesia: Victory or Defeat?," by an unidentified author, 1965 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - "Indonesia: Victory or Defeat?," by an unidentified author, 1968 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - "In Czechoslovakia, The West is Checkmated," by J. B. C. Woods, 1968 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - "On the Life of Lucien Labaudt," by Emily Maloney, 1969 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - "On the Life of Lucien Labaudt," by Emily Maloney, 1969 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - "Introduction to Bancroft Library Tape of Walter Packard", by Allan Temko, 1970 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - "Emmy Lou Packard," by Claudia Lettman Bubeck for the Womans' Art Caucus, 1979 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - "A Short Biography of Emmy Lou Packard," by Nikki Bridges, 1980 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - "As We Live and Perceive," by Sydney H. Williams, 1984 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Poem: "Foothill Bay: A Vivid and Ironic Saga," by Sydney H. Williams, 1984 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
- Art Work, 1921-1976, undated, Series 9:; (Box 6; 10 folders)
  Original art work by Packard and others, including Anton Refregier, possibly Pablo O'Higgins, and Ethel Weiner.
  - Drawings by Packard, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Ink Drawings by Packard, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Linoleum Block Print by Packard, undated (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Linoleum Block Prints with Silk-screened Color by Packard, 1946 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Linoleum Block Print with ink-drawn details for the Farm Worker invitation by Packard, 1975 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Drawings by Pablo O'Higgins (or possibly by Ethel Weiner), undated (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Woodcut by Anton Refregier, 1921 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Drawings by Ethel Weiner, 1937, undated (Box 6, Reel 5817)
- Exhibition Files, 1950-1964, Series 10:; (Box 6, OV 11; 5 folders)
  Letters, writings, a scrapbook, and miscellaneous printed material relating to exhibitions in which Packard participated. The files for the Randall-Packard Print Exhibition in Moscow contain writings, printed materials, and a scrapbook that includes a postcard, clippings, a translation of a letter from Andrei Chegodaev, a note, a photograph of Dementi Shmarinov of the Artists Union in Moscow, two photographs of the exhibition opening, and an exhibition announcement and catalog.
  - San Francisco Art Festival 1950, San Francisco, California, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Randall-Packard Print Exhibition, Pushkin Museum, Moscow, 1964, (4 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Oversized printed material from the Randall-Packard Print Exhibition, 1964 (Box OV 11, Reel 5817)
- Project Files, 1953-1985, Series 11:; (Box 6-7, 10, OV 11; 1.8 linear feet)
  Files for Packard's commissioned projects and her mural restoration work. Many of the project files contain letters, receipts, notes, art work, photographs, and printed material. Of particular interest are the files documenting Packard's restoration work with the Coit Tower murals in San Francisco and Anton Refregier's murals at the Rincon Annex Post Office in San Francisco. Several of the mural restoration project files include scattered letters from artists, such as Anton Refregier and Reuben Kadish, photographs of artists, and photographs of the murals prior to restoration work.
  - Photographs of Plexiglas Mural, Paper Doll Club, San Francisco, California, undated (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Photographs of Murals completed at Home of Mrs. Stephan Zellerbach, undated (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Library Murals, Hillcrest Elementary School, San Francisco, 1956, (4 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Mural Panels for Various Ships, Matson Navigation Company, San Francisco (includes photographs of the S. S. Mariposa, S. S. Matsonia and the S. S. Lurline, 1956-1972, (3 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Photograph of Insignia for Entrance, A. S. Aloe Company, Seattle, 1959 (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Student Center Bas-Relief, University of California, Berkeley (includes photographs of Byron Randall and of Packard with Paule Anglim and Vernon DeMars), 1959-1979, (7 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Decorative Wall, Diamond Heights Redevelopment Area, San Francisco See Also OV 11, 1964-1968, (6 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Murals and Fountains, Ralph Bollman Water Purification Plant, Concord, California, 1966-1968, undated, (8 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5817)
  - Mural, Fresno Convention Center Theater, Fresno, California, 1966-1972, (17 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5817-5818)
  - Concrete Mural, Mirabeau Restaurant, Oakland, California, 1966-1980, (10 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5818)
  - Brick Mosaic Wall, Pinole Valley Library, Pinole, California (includes a design for a doorway decoration executed in gouache), 1972-1975, (7 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5818)
  - Mural by Mission High School Students (Packard served as technical advisor), 1974-1982, (6 folders) (Box 7, Reel 5818)
  - Photographs of Mural, West Lake Library, Daly City, California, circa 1977 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
  - Photographs of Mural, South San Francisco Boys Club, 1978 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
  - Restoration of Murals by Anton Refregier, Rincon Annex Post Office, San Francisco, California (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Preliminary Reports, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Correspondence (includes 6 letters from Refregier and 1 from Rueben Kadish), 1953-1985, (18 folders) (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Signatures of Petition Sponsors, 1979 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Petitions, undated (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Notes, 1953-1980, undated, (7 folders) (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Receipts, 1980 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Photographs (includes one of Packard with Pete Seeger), undated (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Clippings, 1953-1985, undated, (6 folders) (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Press Releases, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1953-1980 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
  - Restoration of Coit Tower Murals, San Francisco (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Contract, 1975 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Report Notebook of Letters and Photographs, 1975-1984, (2 folders) (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Financial records, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Letters, 1974-1984 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Notes, n.d (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Audiotape of Television Interview of Packard by John Fullmer, undated (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Photographs of Coit Tower artists Ralph Chesse, Lucien Labaudt, Rinaldo Cuneo, Otis Oldfield, and Bernard Zakheim, undated (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Photographs of 1962 restoration by Dorothy Puccinelli Cravath, circa 1962 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Photographs of 1975 restoration by Packard, circa 1975 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1979-1983 (Box 7, Reel 5818)
  - Restoration of Murals by Helen Forbes and Dorothy Puccinelli Cravath, Fleishacker Memorial Mothers' House Children's Building, San Francisco, circa 1975, (2 folders) (Box 7, Reel 5818)
  - Oversized, Murals and Fountains, Ralph Bollman Water Purification Plant, Schematic Drawings and Blueprints, 1968, undated (Box 10 (sol), Reel 5818)
  - Oversized, Concrete Mural, Mirabeau Restaurant, Blueprints, 1967 (Box OV 11, Reel 5818)
- Photographs, 1914-1982, Series 12:; (Box 8, 10; 0.8 linear feet)
  Photographs of Packard, her family, colleagues, residences, art work, miscellaneous art-related events and peace demonstrations. Included in the files are photographs of Packard with Cesar Chavez, Juan O'Gorman, Malvina Reynolds, Charles Safford, Ralph Stackpole, and Tennessee Williams. Also found is one photograph of Emmy Lou Packard signed by Dorothea Lange.
  - Photographs of Emmy Lou Packard (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - With Mother, Sister Clara, Schoolmates, and Son Donald, 1914-1936 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - With Sister, and With Son (See Also Sol 10), circa 1940-1947 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Of Packard (includes one signed on reverse by Dorothea Lange), 1954 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Packard's Wedding to Byron Randall, 1959 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Packard in the studio, with Byron Randall, and with mother (See Also Sol 10), circa 1960 -1971 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Packard in studio, with her sister, with Byron Randall, with Jack Owen, circa 1970-1979 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Packard with her sister, circa 1980 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Oversized, Packard with her sister, and son, circa 1940-1947 (Box 10 (sol), Reel 5819)
    - Oversized, Packard in the Studio, circa 1960 (Box 10 (sol), Reel 5819)
  - Photographs of Family Members (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Burton Cairns as a Child, undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Donald Cairns and Family, 1973-1978 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Byron and Jonathan Randall and of Byron Randall's paintings, 1960s (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Packard and Jack Owen, 1970s (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Packard at Miscellaneous Parties, undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Packard at a Thanksgiving gathering, undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
  - Photographs of Packard with Colleagues and Friends (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Packard with Friends and Colleagues (includes includes Cesar Chavez, Bill Einstein, John Grace (architect), Edgar Kauffman, Juan and Elena O'Gorman, Otis Oldfield, Charles Safford, Ralph Stackpole, Francis Violich, and Tennessee Williams)1935-1976, (4 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Photographs of Charles Safford, circa 1949-1964 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Photographs of Malvina Reynolds, 1966, undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - With Mother, Sister Clara, Schoolmates, and Son Donald, 1914-1936 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
  - Photographs of Residences and Studios (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Ranch near Mendocino, 1960s (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - House and Gallery in Mendocino, 1964, (2 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Construction of Studio at Mendocino and Completed Studio, 1960s (Box 8, Reel 5819)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Events (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Events at the Randall-Packard Gallery, undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Miscellaneous outdoor art exhibitions (include Packard), undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Children's Multi-Culture Institute Art Exhibition (includes Packard), undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Guild Gallery Reception, undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Exhibition of American Graphic Art in Moscow, Russia, 1958 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Russian Art Exhibition at the Randall-Packard Gallery, 1967 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Miscellaneous Peace Demonstrations and Marches, 1964-1971 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - Negatives of Miscellaneous Peace Demonstrations and Marches, 1964-1971 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
  - Photographs of Art Work (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - By Packard, Paintings, 1939-1971, (7 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - By Packard, Plexiglass, undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - By Packard, Sculpture and Mosaics, 1960s (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - By Packard, Prints and Drawings, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - By Packard, Peace Posters Designed by Packard 1964-1978 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - By Others, Prints and paintings by Byron Randall, undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - By Others, Murals and Paintings by Harry Donald Jones, Charles Lobdell, Orozco, 1977 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - By Others, Clay figures and wood sculpture by an unidentified artist, Genni Mucchi, Vladmir Preslik, 1939, 1951, undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - By Others, Illustration by Adolf Born, Monotype by Zdena Fibichova, Drawing by Karel Trinkewitz, undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
    - By Others, Miscellaneous murals, 1973-1982 (Box 8, Reel 5819)
  - Photograph of an Elephant's Trunk, undated (Box 8, Reel 5819)
- Scrapbooks, 1947-1950, undated, Series 13:; (Box 10, 0.2 linear feet)
  Two scrapbooks containing photographs and clippings of art work, commissioned projects, clippings, and other printed materials. Scrapbook 1 contains photographs of art work by Packard including plexiglas art work, murals for the Matson Navigation Company, murals for the residence of Mrs. Stephan Zellerbach, mural for the Hillcrest Elementary School, wallpaper designed for James Kemble Mills, an inlaid table, miscellaneous sculpture. Scrapbook 2 contains clippings, exhibition announcement and catalogs, a photograph of painting, photographs of murals, photographs of Packard, and photographs of plexiglass art work.
  - Scrapbook 1, undated (Box 10, Reel 5819)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1947-1950 (Box 10, Reel 5819)
- Printed Material, 1936-1988, undated, Series 14:; (Box 8-9, 10; 1 linear foot)
  Printed materials, including clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, prospectuses, press releases, calendars of events, announcements for political rallies, programs, brochures, booklets, books, and reproductions of art work.
  - Clippings, 1936-1980, undated, (16 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5819)
  - Clippings, 1981-1988, (6 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5819)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1948-1985, undated, (7 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5819)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1937-1986, undated, (9 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5819-5820)
  - Prospectuses, 1966-1973 (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Press Releases, 1982 (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Calendars of Events (see also Sol 10), 1982-1983 (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Announcements for Political Rallies, 1979-1985, undated (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Programs, 1949-1985, undated (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Brochures, 1952-1985, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - San Francisco City Planning booklets designed by Packard, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Poems North of Mendocino by C. Grant Loomis, 1962 (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Poems The Soul Book by Malvina Reynolds, 1967 (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Booklet Peace Poems by Children, compiled by Mary Rudge, cover art by Packard, 1984 (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Booklet Peace Poems by Children, compiled by Mary Rudge, cover art by Packard, 1984 (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Booklet Peace Poems by Children, compiled by Mary Rudge, cover art by Packard, 1984 (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Miscellaneous booklets, 1977-1982 (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Art of the United States of America, 1675-1975 by André Chegodaev, 1976 (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - San Francisco General Hospital Medical Center Collection, 1978 (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Reproductions of art work by Packard, 1964, undated (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Reproductions of art work by others, undated (Box 9, Reel 5820)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1979-1984, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5820)
- Artifacts, 1984, undated, Series 15:; (Box 9-10, 2 folders)
  An rpm vinyl recording by Malvina Reynolds and a political campaign button.
  - Anti-Reagan Campaign Button, 1984 (Box 9, Reel unfilmed)
  - Vinyl 45rpm record Malvina Reynolds Sings 'Little Boxes' and 'Cement Octopus', undated (Box 10 (sol), Reel unfilmed)